Todd, I know you spoke a little bit
about this in the the final game, but
just what has Lavonte meant for you as a
coach and also just as a person?
Ooh, man, as a coach, he was my eyes and
ears and heartbeat on and off the field,
you know, he would always ask me
what can we do better, what can I do,
who can I get going, how can I talk to
people. It was It went from a
coach-player relationship to more of a
collaboration cuz he was very bright and
he understood what I was trying to get
done, but he understood what the team
needed to get done as well and which
guys needed it and you can't replace
that kind of guy. I mean, it takes years
of trust to build up. Like you said,
when I first met him and we were going
to a 3-4 and initially he thought
his weak-side linebacker position meant
outside backer, but it didn't. It was
really the other inside backer spot and
I kind of showed him and walked him
through it and after the first meeting
he was kind of excited and I knew we
kind of went from there, but
uh to lose somebody like this is, you
know, I'm I'm just happy he got to go
out the way he wanted to go out and you
can't replace that.
What he meant means for everybody in the
building, coaches and players, as an
organization as a whole,
class act, played like it, practiced
like it, uh never took anything for
granted and, you know, that that's what
you want to be. Todd, Lavonte is truly
irreplaceable. That being said, he's
touched a lot of players' lives and he
impacts
Who and maybe how do you go about trying
to
fill that void from a leadership
standpoint that
that has retired and left Well, he's
developed enough leeway now that he's
touched Vita, he's touched Ya-Ya,
obviously Sir Winfield and Tykee here as
well, Nelson, all those guys are
incoming leaders that speak up anyway.
Canady is another one that that will go
about at least on defense. Offensively,
we have enough. Defensively, there will
be that guy that has to speak more, but
that has to come naturally. I think
they've started that process in the last
year or two, so it shouldn't be
difficult for those guys to speak up,
but there'll be a never be another him.
Can you see that influence that he's had
on those guys now on the field?
Everyday. I mean, everyday. I mean, he
took Tykee under his wing, he took
Winfield under his wing.
When Devin was here, he took KJ, he took
Lavonte under his wing. Canady,
obviously they came from the same high
school. No matter what position, he gets
it and he understands what guys need and
he talks to them and he spends time with
them and he gets the most out of them.
Todd, can you recall a moment with with
Lavonte maybe behind the scenes that was
just quintessential Lavonte David
leadership or a moment on or off the
field that has really stuck with you?
I think one day in practice and it might
have been training camp and he ran for a
play and laid out for a ball that he had
no business laying out for and he wasn't
even in pads and, you know, that kind of
said everything that needed to be said
about him. He never went on the field on
a practice day and kind of took the day
off and took a vet day or anything else
like that. We had to make him sit down
and that kind of exemplified everything
that this guy stood for.
What was that like for you getting that
phone call that he was indeed
When I got it, I already knew. I kind of
felt it, you know, it was tough and it
was it was emotional. It was emotional
on both sides and, you know, for him to
spend time with his daughter now, he's
earned that right.
I'm very happy for him that way. There's
a big hole in everybody's heart,
obviously,
uh but in true fashion, the way he talks
and touches everybody, everybody will
move on with his spirit and hopefully
play just like he played. What I mean,
just have all these players past and
present show up for him like that today?
I mean, just what does that say about
the impact on him?
He made a huge impact and even more that
even called him that couldn't make it
today, that were out of town, but he
touched this whole building. You knew
when he came in, he could lead from the
front and he could lead from the back
and that's the essence of a true leader,
you know, whether he put his arm around
you or whether he got on you or whether
he led by example, he did it all. He did
it all, he did it everyday. He did it
with class, he did it with determination
and he did it with heart. Todd, there'll
be quite a debate for him for the Hall
of Fame. You know, he's got the numbers,
the meaning of the game, the variety
and it comes together. If you were going
to present him for the Hall of Fame,
what would you what would you say about
his instinctual abilities and how he
affected the game?
Uh
total effort, understood he was a very
intelligent ball player, had the knack
for making the big plays at the right
time. Uh his work ethic, his practice
habits, his energy,
I've never seen a guy play screens
better than anybody played than he's
played the screens and you look up at
the stat sheet, they speak for
themselves. He practiced that way, he
lived off the field that way, he worked
that way and he is Lavonte David.
>> And then when when Mike went down in
week seven and all his offensive
teammates had that impossible task of
having to go back to the huddle and
regroup, he stayed out on the field with
you and I asked him about that and he
said, "That's my brother." And he didn't
want him to be, you know, alone. He
wanted him to have a teammate out there.
And and also out there to support you.
Like just what what did that
mean for his team?
Well, for me, you know, him and Mike
have been here the longest, so obviously
their bond is deeper than everyone
else's, so they've been here a good 12,
13 years at the same time, so that bond
goes far. They talk about it all the
time how they were here when they were
really bad and they had nobody was in
the stadium and and nothing was around,
so they appreciated every snap and every
practice rep and game rep, so when Mike
went down, Lavonte said all that came
rushing back to him, you know, just
seeing him down there like that, knowing
that he was like one of the few left
that came from that, so they bonded very
well and it meant been a lot.
Oh, it's going to be huge. It's going to
be huge from a from a off-the-field
standpoint. On the field, I think we can
get guys to play and do those type of
things, but off the field, just
understanding your teammates and having
a grasp of the entire building, that's
going to take some time, that's going to
take guys spending time around each
other and again, he spent so much time
with the defensive guys, then Winfield
and Tykee,
two out of about six or seven guys that
can step up on defense understand that
and I think they'll carry that with
them.
Okay, thank you. Yeah. Thank you. Jason,
that was great.